optimispt.com 2014-06-25

# Privacy Policy | OptimisPT

_Effective as of May 1, 2012_  

### Our Commitment to Privacy

Your privacy and the privacy of your clients are very important to us. To better protect your privacy, Optimis _Corp_ provides this notice explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. To make this notice easy to find, we make it available on our homepage and at every point where personally identifiable information may be requested.

**Optimis _Corp_**  
ATTN: Website Security  
24630 Washington Ave.,Suite 200  
Murrieta, CA 92562

### The Information We Collect

This notice applies to all information collected or submitted on the [OptimisPT.com](http://optimispt.com/) website. On some pages, you can make requests to schedule a demo. The types of personal information collected on these pages are: Name, Address, Email Address, Phone Number.

### The Way We Use Information

We use the information you provide about yourself only to learn about your needs for EMR solutions. We do not share this information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to complete the setup of your account.

We use return email addresses to answer the email we receive and communicate with you about Optimis _Corp_ ’s products and services. Such addresses are not shared with outside parties.

Finally, we never use, share, sell or rent the personally identifiable information provided to us online in ways unrelated to the ones described in this privacy policy without also providing you an opportunity to opt-out or otherwise object to such unrelated uses.

### Cookies

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s computer for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies on this site. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site.

We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. We use session cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s “help” file.

We set a persistent cookie to store your passwords, so you don’t have to enter it more than once. Persistent cookies also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site, and identify certain functionality of your web browsing software.  
If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some areas of our site, such as contests or surveys, will be limited.

### Log Files

As is true of most Websites, we and the third party tracking services we use gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes your internet protocol (IP) address, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data.

We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, administer the site, track users’ movements around the site and also to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.

### Newsletters

If you wish to subscribe to our newsletter(s), we will use your name and email address to send the newsletter to you. If you wish to Opt-out of receiving these newsletters you may do so at any time by following the unsubscribe instructions within the emails you receive.

### Service Related Announcements

We will send you strictly service-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email.

Generally, you may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature.

### Referrals

When you register for a demo, you have the opportunity to let us know if you heard about us from somebody you know. If you do, we will give you the opportunity to provide us with your friend’s name, so we can credit him/her with a referral bonus. Optimis _Corp_ stores this information for the sole purpose of providing the referral bonus and tracking the success of our referral program.

If your name has been provided as a referral, you may contact us at [privacy@optimispt.com](mailto:privacy@optimispt.com) to request we no longer store your name.

### Links to Other Sites

This Website contains links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by Optimis _Corp_. Please be aware that we, Optimis _Corp_ , are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites.  
We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Website that collects personally identifiable information.  
This privacy statement applies only to information collected by this Website.

### Public Forums

Our Website will offer publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at [privacy@optimispt.com](mailto:privacy@optimispt.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information.

### Testimonials

We also post customer testimonials/comments/reviews on our Website, which may contain personally identifiable information. If you wish to request that your testimonial be removed, you may do so by contacting us at privacy@optimispt.com

### Service Providers

We use other third parties such as an email service provider to send out emails on our behalf. When you sign up for our services, we will share your personal information only as necessary for the third party to provide that service.

### Legal Disclosure

We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Website.

### Business Transitions

In the event Optimis _Corp_ goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your personally identifiable information will likely be among the assets transferred. You will be notified via email or prominent notice on our Website for 30 days of any such change in ownership or control of your personal information.

### Our Commitment to Data Security

The security of your personal information is important to us. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

### Our Commitment to Children’s Privacy

Protecting the privacy of the very young is especially important. For that reason, we never collect or maintain information at our website from those we actually know are under 13 for sales purposes, and no part of our website is structured to attract anyone under 13. However, some of our clients may have patients who are under 13 and their information would be safely secured in our encrypted database.

### HIPAA at Optimis _Corp_

As a provider of software

Changes to This Policy  
We may update this privacy statement to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes, we will notify you by email (sent to the email address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

### How You Can Access or Correct Your Information

You can access all your personally identifiable information that we collect online and maintain by contacting us at [privacy@optimispt.com](mailto:privacy@optimispt.com) or by submitting a written request to:

Optimis _PT_  
ATTN: Website Security  
24630 Washington Ave., Suite 200  
Murrieta, CA 92562

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services, contact us at [privacy@optimispt.com](mailto:privacy@optimispt.com). We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

We use this procedure to better safeguard your information. You can correct factual errors in your personally identifiable information by sending us a request that credibly shows errors. To protect your privacy and security, we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections.

### How to Contact Us

Should you have other questions or concerns about these privacy policies, please send us an email at [privacy@optimispt.com](mailto:privacy@optimispt.com).
